ANDRES FREIXA SUMIHE

asumihe14@gmail.com | Linkedin: Andres Sumihe | andressumihe.me

SUMMARY

I have a good motivation for progress and growth, eager to learn new things, and can work as an individual or in a team. I have good communication skills, fast learner and can work under pressure. In the past two years, I have worked on several projects like developing two mobile applications; Harkit I-Care and TaniPintar, and other projects related to software development.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Developer Intern

Marikh Salatiga

Sep 2021 – Des 2021, ID

- Develop TaniPintar application. application of agricultural land allocation to help farmers manage land and make it easier for farmers to obtain information related to commodities and harvest amounts from other farmers in a farmer group
- Build API Service for TaniPintar using Next.js (Serveless) and deploy to Oracle Cloud.
- Manage testing, bugs fixing, and deployment to playstore.

Fullstack Developer and Contributor

Arisan Security Salatiga

Jul 2019 - Present, ID

- Contributing as an active member; write and review blog article for blog arisansecurity.id
- Working on web (arisansecurity.id) migration from Wordpress to Gatsby.js (since 2021)
- Manage testing, bugs fixing, and deployment to netlify.

Mobile Developer

PT. Skala Teknologi Nusantara - Part Time

Jul 2021 – Present, ID

- Develop Patient lifestyle tracker and monitoring for Pusat Jantung Nasional Harapan Kita (Harkit I-Care)
- Develop Harkit I-Care app using Flutter, Ghost API and Firebase.
- Manage testing, bugs fixing, and deployment to playstore.

Quality Assurance Analyst Intern

Alfamart Head Office

Jan 2022 – Jun 2022, Tangerang, ID

- Working on corporate scale application migration from VB.NET to Flask (Python based) as IT Quality Assurance.
- Developing test plans, test cases, test scripts, and test reports on Alfamart Property and Development System (PDS) Application and Building Maintenance Technical Support Application.
- Make a test result report.

Business Intelligence Intern

Alfamart Head Office

Jun 2022 – Present, Tangerang, ID

- Develop several Forms for Human Resource Application using flask and webix.
- Work closely with other developers to debug and testing form.
- Using Google Cloud Platform to deploy application.

Satya Wacana Christian University

Assistant Lecturer of Discrete Mathematics Course

Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

• Taught in practical classes with material such as Boolean Algebra, Karnaugh Map and Logic Gate.

Assistant Lecturer of Programming Course

Jan 2020 – Apr 2020

• Taught in practical classes with material such as looping, condition, data type in C, C++ and Java.

Assistant Lecturer of Introduction to Informatics Engineering Course

Sep 2020 – Dec 2020

• Taught in practical classes with material such as what is Informatics field and basic knowledge about IT field.

Assistant Lecturer of Human and Computer Interaction Course

Sep 2020 – Dec 2020

Taught in practical classes with material such as design with Figma and slicing into HTML using bootstrap.

Assistant Lecturer of Network Technology Course

an 2021 – Apr 2021

• Taught in practical classes with subjects related to computer networking, router simulation and how to setup a simple server..

INVOLVEMENT

Chief Executive of Kelompok Bakat Minat NETSOUL (KBM NETSOUL)

Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

- Leading Talent Group and responsible to Senat Mahasiswa Fakultas.
- Manage event and weekly gathering for learning about Networking and Ethical Hacker

Chief Executive of Himpunan Mahasiswa Program studi S1 Teknik Informatika (HMP S1 TI)

• Leading student associations, compiling and running work programme.

Jan 2021 – Dec 2021

- In collaboration with Informatics Engineering Department for manage event and activity such as webinar, workshop or competition

Treasurer of Arisan Security Salatiga

Jul 2019 – Dec 2020

• Manage organization fund.

EDUCATION

SATYA WACANA CHRISTIAN UNIVERSITY

Salatiga, ID

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering;

Cumulative GPA: 3.7

2022

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Dart, PHP.

Known Tools: GNS 3, Virtual Machines (VMware, VirtualBox), Git, Google Cloud Paltform, Servers (Windows, Linux), Visual

Studio Code, Android Studio.

Known Frameworks: Flutter, React Native, Laravel, Flask, Next.js